You've improved so much in just a year. That's not a lot of time. You have my respect, Kaneda.
Nozomi, can I have a word with you before the team chat?
It'll be okay. You're doing great. I wouldn't worry. If you are...
Um, what I mean is, you're fantastic.
that bastard i charged kanada down before he could shoot and somehow he still managed to get
the shot the worst part is that he's the one who saved my ass
the doctor says that he does not have a concussion
although the cut on his forehead is deep so they're trying to stem the bleeding
we have to get it together and regroup kanada's our main obstacle if we watch for counters
except kanada's the whole problem we're so much better than them i don't get it it doesn't make
sense you don't understand something and suddenly you can't play soccer anymore kind of pathetic
knock it off you too you need to form a solid defensive unit if you don't there's no way we
can win both center backs are key in this formation if you guys hadn't ruined it with your crap we
wouldn't have let them score that's not true asuri back off i agree with you that takashima and togeshi
lack cohesion on defense defenders always want to focus on the times they allowed the other team to
score but i prefer to see the big picture they're defending against numbers all while barking
instructions and chasing the ball and that's without even mentioning the quality of their long
passes they have initiated every single attack in today's game the rest of you may not have realized
it but when it comes to their all-around skills those two are the best defenders for this team
which is all the more reason i expect them to put aside their issues and play in harmony going forward
tokashi look
please listen and try to hear me
i'm back i want in on this chat
whoa hey kureta
i want to keep playing
kureta don't be such an idiot you still need to recover
coach nozomi will you please let me play closer to the defensive line in the second half
all right
i'm counting on you kureta
how are you going to provide defensive cover when you're about to fall flat on your face
sounds like a big risk for not a lot of payoff if you ask me
if you don't want to talk to me then that's fine
just stand there and be useless
it shouldn't be too hard for you
what did you say to me
this team cannot lose because of an error that i made
my pride won't allow it
it's a big deal to you isn't it
this youth team pride that you cling to
so what does that say about you togashi
what
what do you mean
he's moved on and looking ahead
so what is my problem
listen guys
the team needs the three of you to communicate better
to be making eye contact
dust off your empathy
and try to understand each other
when i got to do that with asuri and kureta in the match against sekio
it expanded my overall concept of soccer
if you do that figure out a way to work in sync
it'd change so much
and man i'd love to see it
shut up
what aoi is saying is correct
it comes down to pressing and covering
so when the other team is on the attack
sync up and think fast
you have to decide who's going after the ball and which one is staying back
togashi takashima
i'm sure that you guys have worked out some rules
however
there's nothing better than direct communication
i want you to make a clear agreement
can i say something first takashima
yeah sure
you can just listen to us without saying anything if you want
yeah we'll have a one-sided conversation
togashi
we all want to win this game
please understand that
now that i think of it
this sort of thing never happens
nozomi is giving out such specific instructions
what the heck
so what's your plan
you're the only one who can rally them
i want to leave it in their hands
they need to spot their own problems
talk it out
they should be able to work through these things together
as coaches
we're only here to guide them
we can't hold their hands the entire time
well sure that's the difference between teaching and coaching right
when you teach you tell them all the answers
but coaching is when you guide them in such a way that they come up with the right answers for themselves
you're right
that would be the ideal
but you know maybe you could throw them a tiny bone
i'm never quite sure what i need to do to help them grow as they should it's such a fine line
and at the end of the day i'm not strong like you are
all our players are imperfect nozomi
it's fine
because we are as well
the manager's not a god man
for real
so do yourself a favor and loosen up
if you want to say something to them just do it
that said everyone on this team is relying on you
and a team that looks up to their manager is a great sign
it's your team for a reason nozomi
you got this
all right
it's the second half
let's turn this around
yeah
uh-huh
ashto
hold on a sec
you need to stop trying to put yourself in a position to finish it
wait
how did you know
you're better than that
don't cheapen your talent
so you're saying you don't want me to score right
at what point did i say that you couldn't score
if a fullback gets a shot at a goal
of course they should take it
that's not a question
all i'm saying is that right now
you're moving people around you
without even meaning to
does that make sense to you
if you go around arranging things so that you're the one who gets the goal in the end
you're basically dismantling the team's ideal formation
Otomo
the left wing
leave it Tachibana
Otomo there
starting on the left side of midfield it creates an invisible stagnation
i know you're bothered by it
but the interception isn't the main reason the team conceded that goal
fact is
before that interception took place
a stagnation had set in which weakened the cohesion of the back line
stagnation
it's something you can only sense and not within the individual
only when observing the team is it revealed
okay
i get it
great
then this is the next step ashito
we're going to limit the players you're allowed to instruct during the game
Tachibana
Otomo too
and Kureda
are all yours
you can't instruct any other players
that's one thing
next up
watch out for the defense
make sure they're impenetrable before you move
pro fullbacks only go upfield when they aren't leaving a hole to fill
look old man
you promised me you'd take me to the world stage
if i become a defender now
throw away hope of ever playing forward
and continue listening to your questionable advice
then what
will i get to play on the world stage
not my call
if you grow up based on someone else's plan then you won't amount to anything in the end
that's how managers are
we're desperate for players to go further than their wildest imaginings
the heck does that mean
that tells me nothing
go beyond my wildest dreams for you
if you want to play on the world stage then make it your top priority
i know you'll get there
can you say something to me?
huh?
as like my fan
you know
to me
from you
cool?
pretty please
do your best
don't lose
fight to your limits
sweet
well i'll be taking off now
even with half time it's extremely unlikely they've managed to get their act together
nothing changes
just keep feeding me the ball like before
that's going to be the only way we can beat them at this point
i'm sure you all see that
do what he says
send all balls to kanada and he'll score for us
and keep up the attacks
let's wrap this thing up fast
let's go
yeah!
don't stop moving
focus
here they come tokashi
very interesting tokashi
Very interesting, Togashi. I hear you've had a few run-ins with the police.
It just wouldn't be right for us to risk you hurting the other kids, you know?
So I think you better go on home for the day.
Might be best if you only show up for the gangs.
It's not you, it's those guys. They get a little freaked out and don't do their best.
Coach Fukuda. I'll just go to Esperion and learn from him.
I've been looking forward to working with all of you. I'm the B-team manager.
Was Nozomi Dante even a J-leaguer? Where the hell is Fukuda? So frustrating.
Togashi, you just continue to follow Fukuda's instructions.
Copy that. No attacking allowed until I have the defense covered first. Got it.
I know it's not easy, but you're doing a great job.
Togashi, you were really strong today.
Oh, yeah. My assist on Yoshitsune's goal. You happy we won?
Of course I am, but I meant your self-sacrificing defense.
Even when the rest of the team went all out on the attack,
at the very first sign of danger, you just dropped right back into your position.
This team owes everything to your defensive skills.
Your only flaw is that you pick up too many yellow cards.
Those other teams are just lightweight.
If you're telling me to be less physical, then I don't know what...
It's not what I'm saying.
I know you're not roughhousing players.
It would be too obvious.
At your size, any referee would have to call a foul.
I'm not asking you to dial anything back.
Keep that fighting spirit of yours.
You're all right. Just the way you are.
I got this one.
That bastard Takashima has some mad defending skills.
It's the way he makes his next move unpredictable.
He's got an excellent sense for maintaining distance.
He knows how to gauge the speed of the other player.
And then he puts pressure on him right at the exact moment they hope he doesn't.
Kaneda, here!
Since Takashima put pressure on him right there,
other dudes got no choice but to pass it to Kaneda.
In other words, he made him pass it this way.
That's what you were trying to do, wasn't it?
Damn it!
Takashima, no lie, I hate your guts.
But you're the only one who plays the way that you do.
And you're a master at timing and closing down players.
I'm thinking you should keep doing the pressing.
I'll hang back here and cover.
You lead the dance, so to speak.
Huh?
What can I do?
Feels like I don't have a choice.
I don't want to embarrass him.
All right, I hear you.
But there's one other problem.
Yeah, Kaneda.
If we don't stop him, we're not going to win this game.
When Kaneda attacks, just move aside.
I'll put an end to him.
Trust me.
For what it's worth, I seriously hate your guts, too.
But besides all that,
the only thing I hate even more than seeing your dumb face
is knowing that you're the only one
who can truly intimidate Kaneda.
Okay.
I'm putting my trust in you.
Center backs who aren't even in sync,
don't scare me one bit!
Think you can stop me, punk?
What the heck happened during halftime?
Got it!
Hey, you idiot!
Don't let yourself get pincered!
Kick it out!
Come on, right now?
We were in a good position!
Dust off your empathy
and try to understand each other.
There's something Aoi said
that has stayed with me more than anything else.
What?
He said I should try to understand you more.
So I did, and...
Oh!
I realized you're unique.
Out of all the center backs I've partnered with,
you...
you gotta be...
Oh!
The dumbest, stupidest ass!
Kurira!
The way you play,
every movement has a point, right?
It's obvious enough just from watching.
You don't make a move unless there's logic behind it.
Pretty sure I play like everyone.
Yeah, I know.
You take it to the extreme, my friend.
You're such a logic fiend.
And you were like that even as a kid.
Unwavering.
That's really something.
Hey!
We're restarting.
Better make sure you guys hydrate.
I hope you realize
this doesn't mean we're friends now, Togashi.
You're the kind of dude that I ding-dong ditch.
You're lucky I don't know where you live.
Unwavering.
That's you too, Togashi.
Oh, you little shit!
What the heck are they doing?
Who goes after a ball
that's been thrown back in after an injury?
To the wing?
Damn it.
Damn you!
Well, well, Kaneda.
I knew that you'd run.
Thankfully, you ran right where I expected you to.
What?
You guys, it isn't against the rules
to go after a ball that's been given back.
But that conduct was...
Shut up, all right?
I know what happened.
Kaneda.
I had a lot of respect for you until halftime.
But now, it's like you went back.
You're the same as you were last year.
What?
So step off!
Because it's our turn now!
Do your best.
Don't lose.
Fight to your limits.
Keep calm!
Forget the highline!
And stand your ground!
Watch out for the defense.
The defense.
With Togashi, Takashima, and Kurata
working as a unit now,
all I really have to do is support them.
I'm not saying that
because I want to go on the attack.
It's just...
That is how strong they are together.
Which means next up.
Asari.
Damn.
They've all pulled back
and they're really compact now.
Segurata!
Are you kidding?
All of them have dropped back.
So what should I do?
Huh?
Oh.
Both fullbacks are...
They've pushed all the way up
on both wings.
Are they mocking us?
Both their fullbacks
have totally abandoned
the defensive line.
This is the perfect time
to pass me the damn ball!
Damn.
I haven't had this view
of the field in a while.
Oh, man.
It's nice.
What's that guy's problem?
Why is he looking at us like that?
I'm gonna go mark the creepy kid.
You all stay right where you are!
Stagnation.
I like that word.
It's all starting to make sense now.
It's just like at the tryouts
and in the Sekio match.
No.
It's more vivid and clearer
than it was before.
It's wild.
This guy's got it coming.
I'll show him how useless it is
for a fullback to push up
without a plan.
Stagnation.
Has your perspective changed?
What do your eyes see now?
They're far more sophisticated
than they were back then
during the Sekio match.
Think about it
over and over
and then
move on instinct!
Ashito!
Muto!
You're supposed to be marking him!
What are you doing?
Don't let him break free!
Ashito!
Tachibana!
They're both in a good position
to take a shot.
So who do I pass it to?
Who?
Ashito!
I knew it'd be you!
What the heck is happening?
What's he trying to do?
The right-side fullback?
No way!
You're not gonna shoot!
That's it.
He's through.
Yeah!
Next time on Aowashi,
From Now!
Go to now!
Go!
Next time on Aowashi
This time on Aowashi,
From Now!
Go to now!
Go!
Come!